Institutional Research, Office of; Records ua030
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Office of Institutional Research, Planning and Effectiveness Records
1929-2017
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
ua030
5.7 cubic ft.
Contains studies and reports on the State University of New York at Albany based on research conducted by the Office of Institutional Research.
Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.
Historical Note
The Office of Institutional Research, Planning and Effectiveness is a major source of official data and statistics about the University. The Office has been a key developer of campus enrollment and revenue projections, especially concentrating on undergraduate admissions and financial aid databases. The Office also conducts special studies and databased analyses which measure organizational effectiveness and which support campus management.
Scope and Contents
The Reports and Presentations series of this collection documents the day-to-day work done by the Office. It includes studies and reports completed by the Office on topics including faculty workload and salary; enrollment figures, goals and projections; tuition and student charges; degrees awarded; five year planning background documentation and outcome assessments. This series also includes both internal office correspondence and correspondence with a number of other offices and departments within the university. This collection also contains a series of outcome assessments and correspondence documenting the work done by the Office of Assessment, a subsidiary within the Office of Institutional Research. Finally, this collection includes a series of web crawls of the Office's website.
Arrangement of the Collection
Collection was maintained in the original order after it was transferred.
Educational evaluation; School enrollment; Workload; Annual reports; Administrative records; UAlbany Academic Administration; State University of New York at Albany
- Reports and Presentations, 1929-2004; 4.2 cubic ft.
  Arrangement
  Series was maintained in the original order after it was transferred.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains a number of files documenting the activities of the Office of Institutional Research. This includes university profiles, and prepared presentations and reports on a number of different topics including staff salaries, staff workload analyses, enrollment projections, degree awarding trends, five year plans, student outcome assessments and the Student Information Retrieval System (SIRS) implemented in the 1980s. This series also includes departmental correspondence interspersed throughout.
  - Final Report of the Special Committee on Planning, Budgeting and Information Management, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Inventory of Data Systems in SUNY Central Administration, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Fall 1966 Faculty Course Loads (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Faculty Course Loads, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Spring 1966 Course Loads, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Student Information Management System, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Fall 1963 Faculty Course Loads (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Dates and Functional Analysis Report, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - SIRS User Survey of Functions and Needs (1 of 2), Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - SIRS User Survey of Functions and Needs (1 of 2), Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - SIRS Data Element Definition Group Final Report, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - SIRS Sub-Committee Memoranda, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - SIRS Memoranda, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - SIRS Reports, 1983-1985 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - SIRS Student Registration Memorandums, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - ADAPT System Memorandums, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - SIRS Implantation and Terminal Installation, 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence with SIRS Design, 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - College of Humanities and Fine Arts (1 of 2), 1989 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - College of Humanities and Fine Arts (1 of 2), 1989 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - North East Association for Institutional Research Conference Program and Slides, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - The Nelson A. Rockefeller College Of Public Affairs and Policy Progress Report (1988-89) on Five Year Place, 1987-1992 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - College Of Science & Mathematics, Five Year Place Submitted By Daniel L. Wulff, Dean (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - College of Social and Behavioral Sciences Five- Year Plan Update, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Division of University Advancement, Five Year Plan, 1990-1994 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - School of Education Five-Year Plan, Submitted by Robert H. Koff, Dean, 1990-1994; 1989 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - School of Public Health Progress Report, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - "State University of New York at Albany: A Data Booklet" Prepared for Herman B. Wells & Sidney B. Tickton, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - "Prospectors for The University Center at Albany, 1973- 80" (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - " SUNY A: Mission, Programs, & Priorities for Action, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - University Library Annual Reports, 1972-1997 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - University Library Annual Reports, 1981-1983 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - University Library Annual Reports, 1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - University Library Self- Studies Reports, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - University Libraries Self- Study Report, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - University Libraries 1982- 1987 Five Year Plan, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - University Libraries Five- Year Plan Update, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - University Libraries Five- Year Plan Update, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Reference & Collocational Development Services Department Annual Report, 1977-1978; 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Reference & Collocational Development Services Department Annual Report, 1979-1980; 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - References Services Division Annual Report, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - University Libraries Five- Year Plan Update, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - University Libraries Strategic Plan for 1990- 1995 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - References Services Division Annual Report, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Race Relations Survey, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Office of Institutional Research Five- Year Plan Progress Report, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Campus Enrollment Growth and Goals, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Enrollment, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Enrollment, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Enrollment, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Enrollment, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Enrollment, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Enrollment, 1971-1977 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Full-Time Enrollment, 1929-1964 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Board of Regents Policy on Honorary Degrees, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Outreach Materials, 2014 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Doctoral Thesis Directory, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Promotional Foldout, Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - School of Education Dissertation Tittles, 1979-1985; 1986 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Outcomes Assessment Report, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Enrollment Analysis, Teaching Loads and University Profile, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Dwight Smith, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Institutional Research, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Salary Reports and planning Questionnaires, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Prepared Reports, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Faculty Workload and Class Size Reports, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Enrollment Data, 1968-1980 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Departmental Memorandums, 1967-1969 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Departmental Memorandums, Prepared Presentations Correspondence, 1970-1984 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Departmental Memorandums, Prepared Presentations Correspondence, 1967-1975 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Departmental Memorandums, Prepared Presentations Correspondence, 1969-1975 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Departmental Memorandums and Prepared Reports, 1970-1979 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Degrees Awarded, 1968-1975 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Faculty Load, 1957-1962 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Departmental Memorandum and Presentations, 1967-1970 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Departmental Memoranda and Presentations, 1971-1973 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Departmental Memorandums, 1974-1985 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Semester Enrollment Profiles, 1971-1976 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Departmental Reviews, Reports and Surveys, 1977-1986 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Academic Faculty Salary Reports, 1968-1979 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Faculty Tenure and Workload Analysis, 1970-1976 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Enrollment Data and Projections, 1963-1977 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Salary Schedules and Adjustments, 1946-1978 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Student Outcome Report, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Resource Management, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Semester Enrollment Profiles, 1972-1979 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Enrollment Faculty Allocation and Salary Data, 1967-1979 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence from Dwight C. Smith, 1969-1977 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Office of the Director Correspondence - Office of Institutional Research, 1966 July-1972 October (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Enrollments Growth Master Plan, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Departmental Prepared Publications, 1969-1976 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Ad Hoc Planning Group Memorandums and Correspondence, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Institutional Research Annual Report, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Prepared Reports on Enrollment and Long-Term Planning, 1967-1975 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - "Where are the Women?" Title IX Self Study, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Distribution of Graduate FTE Overhead Transparency, 1975-1986 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Changes in Students' Preceptors of the Importance of Three Major Goals of College Student Outcomes Project Report No. 2, 1984 January (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - "Assessment in The Undergraduate Major", 1992 April (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Departmental Assessment Plans, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - The Carillon, 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Survey on Academic Calendar, 1977 March (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - "Albany Ahead An Historic City's Bright Future" A Report by The Major's Strategic Planning Committee, 1985 February (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - "Alumni Assess the Undergraduate Experience", 1992 March (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - "A Study of Albany Alumni Who Graduated From Sixteen of the Largest Undergraduate Majors", 1992 April (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - "Pre-College Characteristics And Freshmen Year Experiences of predictors of 8-year Albany Outcomes", 1992 November (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Outcomes Assessment 1990s Survey Results, 1998 March (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - "Retention, Academic Outcomes, and Educational Experiences Among Project Renaissance and other Albany Freshmen", 1998 February (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - "An Outcomes-Driven Program of Academic Advisement", 2002 July (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - "Report on The Spring 2001 Presidential Scholars Web-Based Survey", 2001 July (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - "Outcomes Assessment at Albany A Summary of What We have Learned Since 1978", 1992 July (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - "The Undergraduate Experiences Most Strongly Associated with Ten educational Outcomes at Albany", 1993 July (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - "General Education Skill Attainment Reported by Five Groups of Albany Seniors", 1993 February (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Outcomes Assessment at Albany 1994 Survey results, 1995 March (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - "Assessing Student Attainment in The Academic Major", ca. 1990 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - "The Impact of Departmental Research and Teaching Climates on Undergraduate Growth and Satisfaction", 1994 April (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - "Promoting Student Success and Retention: A Summary of what works", 1995 September (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Assessment, Annual Report, 1989 June (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - "A Multi Year Analysis of Albany Student Responses to Opinion Surveys", 1990 August (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - "Albany Graduates from Five Fields of Study: A 1987 Description And Assessment of the Graduate and undergraduate Alumni in Business, Chemistry, English, History and Social Welfare, 1989 February (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - "Retention and Graduation Rates of Albany Undergraduates", 1989 April (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - "Assessing The Impact of The Undergraduate General Education Program", 1988 January (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - "A Study of Graduating Seniors at Albany Comparing Those who Entered As Freshmen with those who entered as transfer students", 1987 November (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Principles of Assessment, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Report of The Assessment Panel, 1990 March (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Report of The Assessment Panel, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Report to The Educational Policies Council From the Committee on Evaluation Policy, 1989 April (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Report to the EPC Committee on Evaluation Policy, 1989 April (Box 5, Folder 33)
- Wendell Lorang Space Management Committee Records, 1980-1986; 1.33 cubic ft.
  Collection was maintained in the original order after it was transferred.
  This series is made up of documents collected and created by Wendell Lorang, Associate Director of Institutional Research and Chair of the Space Management Committee. The documents in this series include correspondence, memoranda regarding space allocations, renovation and alteration requests, classroom move requests, and committee meeting minutes.
  - Space Alterations, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Space Alteration Documentation, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - History Department Move and Renovation Correspondence, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Building Committee Correspondence, 1986-1989 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Arts and Sciences Dean Office Move, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Center for Government Technology Move, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Paint / Carpet Committee, 1987-1989 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Alterations and Renovation Requests, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Space Use Correspondence, 1986-1996 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - ASU/US Project, Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Space Use Correspondence, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Space - Use Alterations (1 of 2), 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Space - Use Alterations (2 of 2), 1994-1996 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Sum 88 Space Projects, Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Alterations, Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Renovation Requisition, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Air Conditioning Requested, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Anthropology Lab Issues and Correspondence, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Resource Department, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Alterations, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Resources Development Moves, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Space Management Committee on Downtown Campus Memoranda and Minutes, 1971-1977 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Space Request Memoranda Proposals, 1980-1986 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Space Management Committee Memoranda, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Continuing Education Program Space Memoranda, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Social Science Building Space Issues Memoranda, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Computing Center Space Rehabilitation Memoranda, 1984-1986 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Summer 1986 Work Requested and Memoranda, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Space Management Committee Binder (Polices), 1977-1980 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Space Management Committee Binder (Minutes), 1977-1981 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Space Management Committee Binder (Space Request AD - Space Request Downtown ), 1977-1981 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Space Alternation Requests and Approval Memoranda, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Space Alternation Requests and Approval Memoranda, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Space Allocation Requests and Approval Memoranda, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Office of Assessment Files, 1993-1999; 0.17 cubic ft.
  Series was maintained in its original order after it was transferred.
  Contents
  This series contains outcome assessment reports, example surveys to be furnished to students, and departmental self-studies on how best to measure student success in a given major.
  - Outcomes Assessment Report and Student Surveys, 1992-1999 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Assessment in the Major Memoranda and Department Reports, 1993-1999 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Modified Assessment Plans For Assessment in the Major, 1990-1994 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Website of the Office of Institutional Research, 2013 May 8-2018 August 2018; 435 captures